Guide to the George Y. Shevelov Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series III: Documents, Biographical and Background Materials, 1945-2000
  - Biographical and Background Materials:
    - Reviews on his writings, 1948-1998 (including enclosures found in the books):
      - Ukrainische Schriftsprache 1798-1965. (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Bibliography of Shevelov's works: (Box 30, Folder 4 to 5)
      - Iurii Volodymyrovych Shevel'ov (Iurii Sherekh): Materiialy do bibliohrafii. New York, 1998 (Box 30, Folder 4)
      - List of works (Box 30, Folder 5)
- Series IV: Photographs, 1922-1994
  This series contains color prints of group and individual Shevelov's photographs. There is also black and white prints of Vasyl' Simovych and his family and friends photographs dated 1922-1923.
  - Hrozyk, Hana; et al., 1943-1944 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Hrozyk, Pavlo; et al., 1943-1944 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Laslo-Ku(?), M., Kharkiv, 1976 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Mel'nyk, V., Kharkiv, 1976 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Nakonechna, Hanna, 1923 1943 (2 prints of group photographs) (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Nedil's'kyi, Ivan, 1922-1923 (3 prints of groups photographs) (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Shevelov, Iurii, unidentified place, Kaniv, Kharkiv, 1943-1994 (9 prints of group and individual photographs) (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Simovych, Dora, 1922-1923 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Simovych, Marusia, 1922-1923 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Simovych, Roman, 1922-1923 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Simovych, Vasyl', Berlin, L'viv, 1922-1940s (5 prints of group and individual photographs) (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Stots'kyi, Nestor, 1922 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Voievodka, Kost', 1922 (Box 30, Folder 6)
- Series V: Writings by others, undated, 1970s-2001
  Contains typescripts and holograph manuscripts of writings by various authors and books edited by Shevel'ov; many with authors' inscriptions.
  - Barka, Vasyl', "Vorgesang," undated (carbon copy of poem's typescript) (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Bondar-Tereshchenko, Ihor. “My chasom buvaly nespravedlyvi”: see Series I: Correspondence--Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals--Bondar-Thereshchenko (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Danylenko, Andrii, Lev Chaban. Iurii Volodymyrovych Shevel'ov (Iurii Sherekh): Materiialy do bibliohrafii, 1998 see Series III: Documents and Biographical and Background Materials--Bibliography
  - Dvorko, Henrikh. "Ukraina-IEvropa-Amerykans'kyi diad'ko": see Series I: Correspondence--Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals--Dvorko (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Fishbein, Moisei: see Series I: Correspondence--Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals--Fishbein (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Gvynt, Hennadii. Poetry: see Series I: Correspondence--Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals--Hurko, Stefaniia (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Holod, Mariia: see Series I: Correspondence--Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals--Holod (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Hundorova, Tamara. "Bu-ba-bu, karnaval i kich," undated (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Hurko, Stefaniia. Poetry: see Series I:Correspondence--Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals--Hurko, Stefaniia (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Kachurovs'kyi, Ihor. Radioscript dedicated to Shevelov's 75 anniversary, 1983 see Series I:Correspondence--Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals--Kachurovs'kyi (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Koneski, Blaze. A historical phonology of the Macedonian language, 1983. Edited by G.Shevelov (with Shevelov's margin notes) (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Korchyns'ka, (?). "Shcho zalyshylosia v pam'iati pro profesora Vasylia Simovycha": see Series I: Correspondence--Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals--Stefanyk, Iurii (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Krajcovic, Rudolf. A historical phonology of the Slovak language, 1975. Edited by G.Shevelov (with Shevelov's inscription) (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Kurilova, Liudmila. "Kratkoe posleslovie" (holograph manuscript of article about Zerov) (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Livyts'ka-Kholodna, Natalia. Poetry, 1986-1987 see Series I: Correspondence--Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals--Livyts'ka-Kholodna, Natalia (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Moskalenko, M.. "Trahediia Lesia Kurbasa," 2001 (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Ostrowski, Donald. "Textual criticism and the Povest' vremennykh let: some theoretical considerations": see Series I: Correspondence--Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals--Ostrowski, Donald (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Rusova, S.. "Dmytro Markovych: posmertna zhadka, undated" (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Ryndyk, S.. "Iurko Budymyr", poem, undated (holograph manuscript) (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Schaarschmidt, Gunter. The historical phonology of the Upper and Lower Sorbian Languages. 1998. Edited by G.Shevelov (book inscribed by author) (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Slavutych, Iar. "Zhyvi smoloskypy", "Svitlychnyi", 1979 1980 (typescript): see Series I: Correspondence --Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals--Slavutych (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Stasiv-Kalynets', Iryna. Lyst, undated (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Sverstiuk, Ievhen. Poetry, 1981-1982): see Series I: Correspondence --Subseries I.1: Correspondence with Individuals--Sverstiuk (Box 13, Folder 17) and --Luckyj (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Wexler, Paul. A historical phonology of the Belorussian language, 1977. Edited by G.Shevelov (with Shevelov's inscription) (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - Unidentified, undated (Box 30, Folder 17)